What is happening in Iran? In this
video, we're going to break down all of
the latest, including Donald Trump
arguing that we might walk away from
nuclear discussions with Iran. We'll
talk about the Fineberg directive that
was just leaked where the Pentagon is
begging defense firms to build weapons
as the Iran war deplate stockpiles. In
addition to that, we will analyze Rathon
stock ticker RTX and LMT Loheed Martin
because both of those are seeing
increasing contracts and to some extent
increasing margins because bombs have
pretty good pricing power. Some would
say there is no war without PPE. But
when there's war, there's PPE. Pricing
power in the munitions, right? because
the government pays. Anyway, we're also
going to talk about some of the other
headlines coming across the tape. If you
want free access to the tape for now, go
ahead and check it out. You can get it.
This is what it looks like. Trump says
the US is lowkeying it with Iran. We'll
talk about this. Breaking Iran to
release footage of the Supreme Leader.
You could get these as they come through
tick for tick. I filtered this just down
to Iran, but you could get this tick for
tick if you download the Meet Kevin app
in the Android or Apple App Store.
Totally for free to use this wire
service, by the way. It costs us like an
arm and a leg to provide it, but it's
pretty good. Uh anyway, let's get into
the actual content here because there is
a lot to talk about and I hate to say
it, but as usual, it seems like a war is
the troops will be home for before
Christmas, no more. In other words, my
guess is this is unfortunately going to
last a whole lot longer and Donald Trump
is seeking a strategic pause while at
the same time he's reloading. We just
heard leaked evidence that Bloomberg and
the Washington Post have gotten their
hands on that a Fineberg directive uh
Fineberg is Steve Fineberg, he's the
deputy defense secretary, uh who wrote
on August 5th to defense leaders like
Lockheed and Rathon and so on, uh a
letter directing them to propose
accelerated delivery schedules and
increase production and uh provide sort
of a plan for that within 21 days. They
want to plan for interceptors, missile
tracking, air defense sensors, wide area
surveillance, you name it. It's worth
knowing what we've already gone through.
In like the first period of this war,
the first 30 days of this war, we blew
through 850 tomahawks, 1,000 Patriot and
THAAD missiles, those are interceptors,
and potentially 1300 other ballistic
missiles. Each THAD, by the way, costs
10 to 12 million.
And what's crazy is when you burn 815
tomahawks,
you got to ask yourself how long it took
to make those 850 tomahawks. We started
making those 850 in 2012. It took 14
years of output to produce what we blew
up in 30 days. And now we are in a worse
off position than where we were before
we blew up 14 years of tomahawks. So
obviously Trump is like, "I guess we
need more bombs." [laughter]
Uh, the US Army is is also believed to
have used up virtually all of its um uh
tactical missile and strike missiles and
precision strike missiles. Tripping over
my words there. Uh the Patriot missile
batteries are expected to be near
depletion, if not yet depleted. Uh of
course, Donald Trump counters this. Uh
some say that the reason this comes
through is because you've got generals
going, "Bro, we're out." And they still
have some, but they're really low and
they're like, "Please get Washington to
get us more missiles." Right? And then
of course Trump doesn't want anybody to
feel unsafe. So then of course he goes
on Truth Social. We have more patriots
than anyone else in the world. And that
could also be true because we might have
5% left, but that 5% could still be more
than what anybody else has. [laughter]
It's you always got to kind of read
between the lines. Uh but you know, I I
think there's some poopy dupy in some
people's pants. Or as uh Negan would
say,
I hope you got your pants on.
General Kaine says we need an off-ramp
because this is turning into a problem.
Rathon has just reached a $745 million
new contract for missile defense uh and
another $535 million uh contract for tow
weapon systems. Those are tube launched,
optically tracked, and then either wire
or wireless guide anti-tank or
anti-fortification
missiles. Those are kind of interesting.
Uh, and it's worth noting that their
bomb margins are around 12.6%.
Their commercial Prattton Whitney engine
margins are like 8.3%. Which means
you've got almost 50% more margins in
bombs. That's in addition to, of course,
Collins Aerospace, which is the
afterparts market that has really high
margins at 15.9%.
Aftermarket, it's kind of like with
cars, that's how they get you. you know,
you got a plane down, you're gonna pay
whatever. [laughter]
You know, you got a car that's not
driving, you're gonna pay whatever to
get the darn thing rolling again. You
know, um that's kind of how they can
take advantage of you. I hate to say it,
but take a look at some of the numbers
for uh Rathon and then Loheed Martin and
then let's get into what's actually
going on with Iran and Israel because
it's going to give you an idea of how
much longer this is actually going to
last. And so a lot of people have been
asking me about these two particular
stocks because well that's what I do.
RTX uh has seen net sales increase about
1445%
year-over-year. Their total costs are up
12.75 which does inc indicate an
increase in PP. I do have to say they've
only got $ 8.3 billion in cash with 14
billion in receivables and they have yet
$63 billion of bills. Even if they got
all of their receivables tomorrow, they
would still have nearly three times as
much money in debt that is due within
the next 12 months.
What? Dude, Rathon is basically broke.
[laughter]
A $300 billion company is basically
broke. See, on top of that, then they've
got another $32 billion of long-term
debt. Uh, and another like 7.3 billion
and other long-term. They got a lot of
debt. There's a lot going on here. Now,
even though on a six-month basis, their
net cash flow or their net income is up
33 or 31.5%. And they do have free cash
flow. They got free cash flow about 8.4
on an annualized basis. It's about a
2.8% cash flow yield. That's pretty
good. They've got the cash flow, but
honestly, they need it. They need every
dime of that just to pay their freaking
bills. And what they're actually doing
though in the meantime is they're paying
off about a mill uh sorry a billion
dollars worth of debt and they're paying
nearly $2 billion of dividends in just a
six-month period. This is why Donald
Trump has gotten a little bit pissed.
It's like wait so you have $60 billion
of bills you which is three times as
much in cash as you have and you got a
lot a lot of long-term debt. You're
using your free cash flow. You're using
any of it to what? Did I hear that
right? You're paying dividends. I It's
one thing if you're paying down your
debt, but you're paying dividends. And
so, Donald Trump signed an executive
order. Now, keep in mind, if you cut the
dividends, the stock could tank and that
could then make the company less able to
actually fulfill
more expansion of its capacity, right?
So, so there's like always a give and a
take here, but Donald Trump doesn't
care. We got midterm elections 85 days
away. And so he signed executive order
uh which seeks to ban dividends and
buybacks with [clears throat] immediate
enforcement potential. This actually
doesn't need Congress to make it not
bite. It can already bite today because
he's the commander-in-chief. He can
guide contracts and he can include
restrictive clauses in contracts for new
weapons with these companies that
basically prevent dividends and
buybacks, which I mean, whatever.
they're just going to shift to paying
down their debt, which frankly they
should be doing anyway because, well, at
least RTX is kind of a broky here. But
anyway, uh Donald Trump says this only
applies to underperforming companies,
but underperforming includes the refusal
to de uh deploy corporate capital to
expand and improve physical
manufacturing facilities along with of
course missing deadlines. But it's
actually an or. So, if basically Trump
looks and goes, "Oh, looks like you guys
had uh a lot more cash flow than you
ended up investing. Sounds like you
violated executive order 1437 372." To
me, it's pretty farreaching. It's
actually one of the executive orders
that has bite. Usually, I look at the
EOS and I'm like, "Bro, that doesn't
mean anything. Like, nothing's going to
change, right?" This actually has bite.
And it's no different for Loheed Martin.
Loheed Martin's a smaller company, but
you know, they're getting a $59 billion
deal to triple Patriot missile
production over seven years. Uh the
interesting thing about Loheed Martin,
and then I'll give you a quick price
projection, and then we'll get into some
of these other stocks. Interesting thing
about Loheed Martin is their sales are
up 10.5% and their costs are stable. So,
their PP actually massively exploded. I
mean, for sales to go up 10% and your
cost to go up nothing, incredible. Part
of this is because of a shift to more
F-35 deliveries, which of course there
are higher margins in bombs. Said it
before, and so they make more money on
this stuff, even though doesn't
necessarily cost them more. So that goes
to profit. And so when you look at their
assets, I've got 7 billion of cash and
receivables, 11.6 of bills, plus
another, you know, 29
billion of other long-term debts over
here. So, another company that really
should be paying off their debt, plus
they have as many pension liabilities as
they have cash. That said, their net
earnings did increase 61% year-over-year
on a six-month basis. And they, too, are
uh seeing a cash flow yield of about
3.9%.
2.6 billion of free cash flow in just 6
months. That works out to about 5.2
billion of free cash flow, money that's
not being invested, right? So you see
that's just the difference between this
net cash that they receive 3.4 billion
and their actual capital expenditure is
829 billion. Now in fairness to these
companies they can't blow it all on
capex. They need to have this money for
all the debt they have because they're
so freaking buried in debt. I hate to
say it but they are deep in debt. So of
course this leads a lot of people to say
well Kevin you know what do you think
the valuation is for both both these
companies? I think they're high. I think
both of these companies, I hate to say
it, are overpriced. I mean, you're
looking at this one is Loheed Martin is
sitting at a 3.75 price toearnings
growth ratio. It's because it trades for
19 times earnings, forward earnings
divided by 7% growth puts us at a 275.
That's high for a company with 9%
margins. Rathon's no better. They have
like 8% margins and they're growing at
about 9%. And uh you know, Rathon's got
a three peg. So if you go to our stock
AI where you don't have to wait for
Kevin to tell you, you could just go to
the stock AI tool. You can actually see
the balance sheet is a yellow flag over
here uh on RTX. So it's, you know,
flagging the balance sheet risks. 54%
downside though to get to a fair
valuation for Rathon. Loheed Martin 33%.
I think some this one has, you know,
also the the balance sheet risk. I think
the problem that you're finding is that
these companies are a little hyped up
because of the war that's going on.
People are like, "Oh yeah, of course the
war stocks are going to do well." I
don't know, man. They're between a rock
and a hard place. But I can see why
Donald Trump is pissed and lashing out,
you know, from an optics point of view.
But, you know, in part, all the bombing
we've done also hasn't done great work
at actually accomplishing our mission in
Iran. Now we're seeking a $1.15 trillion
defense budget. All at the same time as
Donald Trump is allegedly quote unquote
lowkeying
the war in Iran. Yeah, that's a new
quote. Trump from an interview with
Axios. Trump to Axio, we are low-keying
it with Iran. Trump wants to allow
economic pressure to amount on Iran like
over time. He thinks the inflation that
they're experiencing is going to kill
them. He thinks that Iran doesn't have
enough money to pay the troops in Iran.
And Trump says we're only
semi-negotiating with them, calling this
a chess match. Uh, hints from US
officials suggest that we're actually
trying to sneak 8 million barrels of oil
at night through the Omani shipping
lanes. That's going to be the uh, you
know, Oman side of the straight of
Hormuz, not the Iranian side. Let's just
look at a map of that really quickly.
problem is it seems like every night we
hear of well maybe not every night but I
mean just last night we heard it or the
night that's over there given the timing
of when we're filming this but uh you
hear regularly including just the last
night in the straight of Hormuz ships
getting attacked and they don't
necessarily know who it is we obviously
know who it is it's the hardliners in
Iran that don't want people using the
Omani side this is Oman right here this
little you know peninsula Right. And
then this over here is Iran.
[clears throat]
I'm announcing that to make it a little
more clear. Iran wants ships to go
around their little islands over here so
they could toll them at 7% or whatever
or just block all US and allied traffic.
Uh Oman is like, um maybe people could
come on this side and we could share
some fees. And the US is like a we'll
just try to sneak some ships by. They're
still getting struck. It's not great.
Not great at all. So this is where Iran
is now saying, "Hey, look, we want more
money. We said we wanted reparations and
then you tried to twist our words into
arguing that this was just, you know, an
established investment from a bunch of
other countries in the Middle East." No,
we want more demands than what we have
previously said. So what do we want? We
want the war in Gaza, Yemen, Iraq, and
Lebanon, and obviously in the straight
of all over. We do not want Iran
threatened anymore. We want the blockade
lifted, which is still in place against
Iran. We want sanctions lifted. We just
added more sanctions Friday, so we're
going in the wrong direction. And Iran
wants full compensation, a full release
of funds as well. Now, this is very
interesting because back in April, those
were the conditions for a nuclear deal.
Now, this has decayed. Those are the
conditions just to get the straight open
again. So, this talk about Donald Trump
going, "Oh, yeah, we're very close to a
deal." No, we're not. This is probably
going to go on for a very long time now.
Markets are kind of turning a blind eye
to this. You know, people are buying the
buying up these defense stocks because I
I don't think they're doing fundamental
analysis on these puppies. I don't
fundamentally these these I mean, the
stocks have performed really well, but I
don't think it's going to last. I mean,
look at look at the relative strength on
RTX. You're sitting at a 71. And this is
in overbought. On the weekly chart, it's
at overbought. Uh on the weekly chart,
you're at 58 on Loheed Martin. So, not
as bad. It's come off some of its highs
a little bit, but I mean, people throw
money at these going, "All right, fine.
The war's going to last longer." But in
the meantime, buy the dip, baby. Market
going to keep going up. Meanwhile, you
know, the uh Bank of America bull bear
indicator is at the highest screaming
sell that I think we have seen ever. I
have a chart of it right here. Uh this
is the bull bear indicator which is at
9.7 which is a screaming sell for Bank
of America. We have been this high
December of 2020, October of 25,
February 26, August 26. You can kind of
see like you know we're we're up here in
the uh extremely bullish side.
[laughter]
uh you know obviously you know we were
over here in um March and so we barely
came down on the bull bear scale right
we got down to like a six but we haven't
been bearish since really well a couple
times in 2023 over here per this you
know scale so
uh in my opinion this unfortunately
is just going to last for a very long
time and I think that's why these
defense stocks are at these high levels
because people look and go, as much as
Donald Trump tacos or says he's going to
walk away from nuclear talks or this,
he's also priming to get more weapons so
we can just keep striking Iran. And so
far, it doesn't actually sound like
we're getting any closer, especially
since BB, who's got an election coming
up in Israel on October 27th, is now
going, "Hey, Trump, f your Gaza deal."
Yeah, BB of Israel literally just said,
"F your Gaza deal, and as long as I'm
prime minister, there will never be a
Palestinian state in Gaza." These are
really aggressive comments that are
either because he's trying to hardline
to say, "Hey, Israel is going to strike
Iran itself. Vote for BB. BB's going to
defend you. Trump's not going to do it.
Vote for BB." Right? That's probably
what's going on in part. But some people
say it's because Donald Trump is quietly
walking away from nuclear talks that
Donald Trump is now saying, "Hey, you
know, we're just [clears throat] going
to walk away." For the Wall Street
Journal, Donald Trump is now privately
quote floating the idea of just walking
away from Iran without a nuclear deal so
that he could declare victory.
Obviously, you know, that needs
confirmation, but if that's true with
midterms 85 days away, that's not really
good. Especially since Donald Trump
doesn't want any taxpayer money going to
Iran, but Iran wants actual reparations.
Like, they're demanding billions to
hundreds of billions of dollars from the
United States to repair the damage that
has been caused. And Trump's going,
"We're not paying that. Hey, other
people can invest in your country, but
we're not paying that." So, Trump is
trying to brand this as, "Oh, yeah,
countries are going to invest in Iran."
Irran's like, "Nah, f you." and the
straits remaining closed.
Well, all that is problematic as is the
fact that we still have not resolved the
very nuclear issue which was the whole
basis for starting the war.
[clears throat]
At the same time, you've got the Houthis
that just struck the Saudi Saudi Aramco
Jazan oil refinery. No injuries
reported. Uh but the Houthis have also
resumed their attacks on the Mocha port
per the Yemeni military. And Houthi
rebels killed 58 government troops on
Thursday, one of the deadliest single
days in years. That's an overlapping
contract. So you got the Houthies
attacking the military in Yemen. And at
the same time, the Houthis are attacking
the Saudis. The reason they're attacking
the Saudis could be because the Sa Saudi
Arabia just signed a defense pact with
Turkey and Pakistan. sort of like a P5
or article five an attack on one is an
attack on all kind of deal.
Israel, by the way, is really pissed
about Pickax Mountain. They call it an
escalating threat. I agree with them.
This was my suspicion since we bombed
uh, you know, Fordo and Espahan during
Operation Midnight Hammer in Natans last
summer. I said, why did we not bomb
Pickax Mountain? Probably because we
can't. That's a problem. Pay attention
to it. Those of you who have been
subscribers here for a while, you know
that I'm not not click baiting that. Uh
so now Israel is ramping their concern
on that. And this isn't a chance for me
to go, "Oh, see, I was right. Pickax
Mountain matters." It's actually a way
of saying, "Crap,
pickaxe mountain matters so much that
the Israelis are like, "Fine, we'll
we'll attack Iran ourselves. We'll keep
the war going." Which, you know,
obviously keeps r the risk elevated that
the straight of Hormuz situation is
going to keep going on for a while. And
so hence, you know, we're seeing uh the
oil market at these elevated prices.
Brent sitting around $80 to $85 here
recently. Uh even though we did get to a
lower dip, that was really only during
the memorandum of misunderstanding. So
we had sort of this false bottom in oil
prices here. And it seems like right now
we're we're balancing out somewhere in
the 80s level, which is certainly a
whole lot higher than where we were at
the end of last year. I mean, the high
at the end of last year was about $70.
low is about $59. A little unfortunate.
The longer this drags on, obviously, the
more inflationary pressures we're going
to see uh for the medium-term, you know,
the next 6 months or more. Uh we got to
get through elections in Israel. We got
to get through elections midterms in
America. Uh there is a chance that this
just unfortunately gets worse before it
gets better. Uh Iran is also getting
stronger with the missiles and the
munitions they're using. For example,
they use these uh Kiar Shakans missiles,
and these can be kept loaded with fuel
versus prior ones that they'd have to
kind of wheel out and then fuel them up,
and they made them easier to target.
This is an example of a destroyed one
right here. This missile can also
allegedly vary its trajectory, which is
really important for avoiding
interceptor attacks. These are deemed to
cost somewhere between 500k to a million
dollars per rocket. cost us somewhere to
between two to five potentially as much
as $10 million to down or intercept
these. And so bottom line uh out of all
of this is I think war stocks are hyped
up. They're full of debt. They are
pricey companies with terrible margins
at the bottom line on the net basis. And
you know Trump's aggression against them
probably isn't going to get Trump what
he wants. Not anytime soon at least. But
it does risk creating some issues for
the stock.
But we'll see. Long-term, they're not
investments that I would make. Could
they perform well for the next six
months under momentum or hype? Sure,
anything can. Uh, next, and that's not
personalized financial advice, just my
opinion. Number two, uh, Donald Trump
royally pissed off BB, at least in part
here, I think. uh which does signal
potential the potential for more
escalation in the Middle East and not
less which does again suggest that these
higher oil prices will last longer and
does unfortunately increase the risk of
the Federal Reserve hiking rates though
they're a little bit of a coin toss for
September right now next straightfor is
likely to remain closed for quite a
while next Iran is ramping up their
demands we're probably not going to get
any kind of nuclear visibility which
does create a longerterm World War II
risk
In the near term, it's a geopolitical
buy the dip. But in the long term, this
nuclear issue is a big poopy dupy and
it's worth being less aggressive and
more careful with debt [music] or just
avoiding debt if you can. Obviously,
there is a very clear also risk that
Iran can escalate during a time in which
we are depleted in weaponry. None of
this is great, but if you want more of
my analysis, including the alpha report
coming out again tomorrow morning for
course members, make sure you go to
meet.com. Join us in the course in the
courses on building your wealth. Next
coupon code expires on Friday. And
folks, we'll see you in the next one.
Goodbye and good luck.
>> Why not advertise [music] these things
that you told us here? I feel like
nobody else knows about this.
>> We'll we'll try a little advertising and
see how it goes.
>> Congratulations, man. You [music] have
done so much. People love you. People
look up to you.
>> Kevin Praath there, financial analyst
and YouTuber. Meet Kevin. Always great
to get your take.